<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>Disable on-the-fly PEP8 checks, only check when saving file</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m using PyCharm Community Edition 4.5.4, and I hate how it notifies me of every little &quot;mistake&quot; I make even when I have full intention of fixing it within 30 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My style is to kind of write everything at once (instead of finishing one thing before moving to the other), and thus every second word in my code gets highlighted as &lt;code&gt;variable &#x27;x&#x27; is not used&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Unresolved reference &#x27;x&#x27;&lt;/code&gt; because I already moved to an other section of my code, intenting to finish the for loop later. If I do something like:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;for x in my_list:    pass&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;And then move to define my_list on top of the file, it will instantly highlight &lt;code&gt;Local variable &#x27;x&#x27; is not used&lt;/code&gt;. I wish to write my whole code freely, and then after hitting save, I wanna know what mistakes I made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is there any way to disable the PEP8 checker, so it would only check when I actually save the file, instead of when I type anything at all? &lt;/p&gt;</Body>
<Tags>python,pycharm,pep8</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;I have had problems with this issue too.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unfortunately&lt;/strong&gt;, there &lt;em&gt;seems&lt;/em&gt; to be no documented way of doing what you&#x27;re requesting. The PyCharm Articles on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/help/code-inspection.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Code Inspection&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.jetbrains.com/pycharm/help/accessing-inspection-settings.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;Configuring Inspections&lt;/a&gt; really don&#x27;t hint at any such possibility.Additionally the config file in &lt;code&gt;~/.PyCharm40/config/inspection/Default.xml&lt;/code&gt; isn&#x27;t what you would call rich in options (&lt;strong&gt;note&lt;/strong&gt;: I have no idea if more options exist, couldn&#x27;t really find appropriate documentation).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;code&gt;pep8.py&lt;/code&gt; is apparently ran continuously as a background process in PyCharm, I also checked whether a configuration of these processes was possible. Unfortunately (&lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt;), no useful results were found. To make things worse, there seems to be no relevant plugin available in their plugin repository to allow for further tweaking of the inspection tool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other option I tried was by changing the settings in PyCharm and resort to &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;manual&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; calls to pep8. I unselected the inspections for pep8 from &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;Settings | Editor | Inspections | Python&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; tab and then ran the manual inspection by pressing &lt;strong&gt;Ctrl + Alt + Shift + I&lt;/strong&gt; and entering the two &lt;code&gt;pep&lt;/code&gt; options. &lt;strong&gt;It does not seem to catch the same coding convention errors&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You probably have two options now, one is switching to another IDE as Adam Smith suggested (or noted, actually) and second is trying to maybe get some help on the &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.jetbrains.com/forum/PyCharm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;PyCharm forum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
