<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>Python dist-packages permissions</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve screwed up some permissions in my dist-packages folder for Python 2.7 and am worried it is going to cause issues.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This stems from an entirely separate issue with imports, which caused me to change the permissions of this folder to test things out.I took the advice to run: &lt;code&gt;chmod -R 775 /usr/local/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When this did not work I attempted to change it back to what it was originally with:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;chmod 765 /usr/local/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;br&gt;Notice the lack of recursive flag. Silly me.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I did an &lt;code&gt;ls -l&lt;/code&gt; I saw I had permissions of &lt;code&gt;drwxrwSr-x&lt;/code&gt; on the folder. It should be &lt;code&gt;drwxrwsr-x&lt;/code&gt; . So I gave it execute permissions with &lt;code&gt;chmod +x&lt;/code&gt; and then setgid - &lt;code&gt;chmod g+s mydir&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ok, so my folder permissions were now back to normal. However in the folder now I see most (not all) of the files are &lt;code&gt;drwxrwSr-x&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What should I do to fix this mess?Here is an excerpt from the messy folder contents:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;drwxrwSr-x  2 root staff    4096 Jul 19 12:48 wheel-0.30.0.dist-infodrwxrwSr-x 12 root staff    4096 Jul 19 12:48 whooshdrwxrwSr-x  2 root staff    4096 Jul 19 12:48 Whoosh-2.7.4.dist-infodrwxrwSr-x  2 root staff    4096 Jul 19 12:48 xmltodict-0.11.0.dist-info-rwxrw-r-x  1 root staff   17356 Jul 19 12:48 xmltodict.py-rwxrw-r-x  1 root staff   15128 Jul 19 12:48 xmltodict.pycdrwxrwSr-x  2 root staff    4096 Jul 19 12:48 yaml-rwxrw-r-x  1 root staff 1115503 Jul 19 12:48 _yaml.so&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</Body>
<Tags>python,file-permissions,chmod</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;There might be shorter ways but I use &lt;code&gt;find&lt;/code&gt; to do a different &lt;code&gt;chmod&lt;/code&gt; on directories than on files. Under dist-packages there are no executable files (at least I have never seen some) so you can do:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;find /usr/local/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/ -type d -exec chmod 755 {} +find /usr/local/lib/python2.7/dist-packages/ -type f -exec chmod 644 {} +&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alternatively you can use &lt;code&gt;775&lt;/code&gt; for the directory (upper) line and &lt;code&gt;664&lt;/code&gt; for the files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are probably going to be symlinks under &lt;code&gt;dist-packages&lt;/code&gt; (there are on my Debian based system), but their &lt;a href=&quot;https://unix.stackexchange.com/a/87202/33055&quot;&gt;permission setting should not matter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
