<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>Updating to ActiveTcl 8.5.17 unexpected behaviour</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;TOday I update from ActiveTcl 8.5.9 to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.activestate.com/activetcl/downloads&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;ActiveTcl 8.5.17&lt;/a&gt;in order to fix this &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/16995969/inertial-scrolling-in-mac-os-x-with-tkinter-and-python&quot;&gt;bug&lt;/a&gt;. I on a mac, os x 10.7. I have noticed to broke a couple things in my program. Some buttons flash a black outline when I click in unrelated areas (This didn&#x27;t happen before the update). By biggest concern is that some of my checkbuttons didn&#x27;t show! For example:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import tkinter as tkt=tk.Tk()c=tk.IntVar()b=tk.Checkbutton(master=t,variable=c)b.grid(column=0,row=1,sticky=&quot;nsew&quot;)t.mainloop()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;gives a empty window &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/kkRpv.png&quot; alt=&quot;window&quot;&gt; however the code:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import tkinter as tkt=tk.Tk()c=tk.IntVar()b=tk.Checkbutton(master=t,variable=c,text=&quot;bob&quot;)b.grid(column=0,row=1,sticky=&quot;nsew&quot;)t.mainloop()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDIT: The Checkbutton is still there as it reacts to click but it just down&#x27;t show&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;gives what is expected. Now comes the weird part, changing the text to &quot;aaa&quot; the code doesn&#x27;t work yet again. Is this something to do with the length of the text? I&#x27;ve tried adding padding, changing the stickiness and nothing helped :( In other cases it acts even weirder. Did something change in 8.5.17 or is my version simply off? &lt;/p&gt;</Body>
<Tags>python,macos,python-3.x,tkinter</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;Use ttk widgets for more cross platform consistency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import tkinter as tkimport tkinter.ttk  as ttk&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;tkk is a set of more modern widget than those presented in tk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I guess tk calls olds OS API for GUI and then customize those widgets. And ttk calls the last, native default API for GUIs.This causes problems on OS X because Apple decided that backward compatibility was not a priority when shipping a new version of their OS &lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
