<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>parsing a deeply nested JSON data present in a .dms file</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;I am trying to parse a deeply nested json data which is saved as .dms file. I saved some transactions of the file as a .json file. When I try json.load() function to read the .json file. I am getting the error as&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;JSONDecodeError: Extra data: line 2 column 1 (char 4392)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opening the .dms file in text editor, I copied 3 transactions from it and saved it as .json file. The transactions in the file are not separated by commas. It is separated by new lines. When I used 1 transaction of it as a .json file and used json.load() function, it successfully read. But when I try the json file with 3 transactions, its showing error. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;import jsond = json.load(open(&#x27;t3.json&#x27;)) or with open(&#x27;t3.json&#x27;) as f:    data = json.load(f)print(data)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;the example transaction is :&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{     &quot;header&quot;:{        &quot;msgType&quot;:&quot;SOURCE_EVENT&quot;,   },   &quot;content&quot;:{        &quot;txntype&quot;:&quot;ums&quot;,      &quot;ISSUE&quot;:{           &quot;REQUEST&quot;:{              &quot;messageTime&quot;:&quot;2019-06-06 21:54:11.492&quot;,            &quot;Code&quot;:&quot;655400&quot;,         },         &quot;RESPONSE&quot;:{              &quot;Time&quot;:&quot;2019-06-06 21:54:11.579&quot;,         }      },      &quot;DATA&quot;:{           &quot;UserId&quot;:&quot;021&quot;,      },{header:{.....}}}{header:{......}}}&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is how my json data from an API looks like. I wrote it in a readable way. But its all continuously written and whenever a header starts it starts from a new line. and the .dms file has 3500 transactions. the two transactions are not even seperated by commas. Its separated by new lines. But within a transaction there are extra spaces in a value. for eg; &quot;company&quot;: &quot;Target   Chips  123 CA&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The output I need:I need to make a csv by extracting values of keys messageType, messageTime, userid from the data for each transaction. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please help out to clear the error and suggest ways to extract the data I need from these transactions for every transaction and put in .csv file for me to do further analysis and machine learning modeling.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
<Tags>python,json,api</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;If each object is contained within a single line, then read one line at a time and decode each line separately:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;with open(fileName, &#x27;r&#x27;) as file_to_read:    for line in filetoread:        json_line = json.loads(line)&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If objects are spread over multiple lines, then ideally try and fix the source of the data, otherwise use my library &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexmojaki/jsonfinder&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;jsonfinder&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/a/40687015/2482744&quot;&gt;Here&lt;/a&gt; is an example answer that may help. &lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
