<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>Python 3.5 Downgraded by conda when I try to install NUMPY 1.10</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;This is getting really frustrating. Whenever I try to install Numpy on the prompt, Python will be downgraded to 2.7 and I can&#x27;t do anything about it. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&#x27;s the ss:&lt;a href=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/515ef.png&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.stack.imgur.com/515ef.png&quot; alt=&quot;enter image description here&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I need a Python 3.5, Numpy 1.10 and scikit-learn 0.17 but I don&#x27;t know how. Anyone knows how to do it? &lt;/p&gt;</Body>
<Tags>python,python-3.x,installation,anaconda</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;blockquote&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Python 3.5, Numpy 1.10 and scikit-learn 0.17&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those versions are on the old side.I imagine you are trying to get as close as possible to the environment used by the author of some tutorial that was written a while ago.A fresh install might give you 1.16 and 0.20.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conda solver was having trouble finding a compatible set of package versions using your python 3.5, which apparently led it to rewind back in time to a fairly early set of versions.I recommend relaxing the constraint, from &quot;equal&quot; to &quot;greater-or-equal&quot;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;conda install numpy&amp;gt;=1.10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you get a somewhat more recent version, the tutorial likely will still work fine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you want to use multiple constraints, you may find it convenient to put them in an &lt;code&gt;environment.yml&lt;/code&gt; file, and use &lt;code&gt;conda env update&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;name: tutorialchannels:  - defaults  - conda-forgedependencies:  - python &amp;gt;= 3.5  - numpy &amp;gt;= 1.10  - scikit-learn &amp;gt;= 0.17&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Remember to use &lt;code&gt;conda activate tutorial&lt;/code&gt; so your &lt;code&gt;PATH&lt;/code&gt; will use that environment.For example, &lt;code&gt;$ which python&lt;/code&gt; will show the newly installed interpreter, and &lt;code&gt;$ python -c &#x27;import pprint, sys; pprint.pprint(sys.path)&#x27;&lt;/code&gt; will mention a directory containing the new numpy library plus a bunch of transitive deps.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
