<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>Python: Method M is a property of Class C; How do I use it inside of C?</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;I want to use a basic function (method), inside the same class that its defined in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&#x27;t know why, but it has to do something with &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This works:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;class What(object):    def worksOnlyOutside(self, a):        print a ** 2    def worksOnlyInside(b):        print b ** 3    worksOnlyInside(2)        #prints out 8What().worksOnlyOutside(3)    #prints out 9&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This doesn&#x27;t work:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;class What(object):    def worksOnlyOutside(self, a):        print a ** 2    def worksOnlyInside(b):        print b ** 3    worksOnlyOutside(2)        #prints out &quot;TypeError: worksOnlyOutside() takes exactly 2 arguments (1 given)&quot;What().worksOnlyInside(3)    #prints out &quot;TypeError: worksOnlyInside() takes exactly 1 argument (2 given)&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;From that I understand that if I want it as an instance outside the class, I need a parameter &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt;. Moreover- to use it internally, I need to skip supplying a &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt; as a parameter.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line: What do I do if I want a method that can both be used inside its class, and be called as a property of that class outside out it?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Class &lt;code&gt;Basic Maths&lt;/code&gt; has a method &lt;code&gt;squared&lt;/code&gt;. It&#x27;s likely I&#x27;ll need it both inside and outside the class, since squaring ints is something you do a lot. There must be another option besides defining two different methods - one with a &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt; to be used externally, and one without it to be used internally.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Thanks guys.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
<Tags>python,class,methods,instance,self</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;If a function is an instance method, its first parameter should be a reference to &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have to guess in your first example, Python is realizing that you intend the method to be called statically, and not requiring the first parameter to be &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you intend the method to be static, don&#x27;t have a &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt; parameter &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you intend the method to be an instance method, have the first parameter be &lt;code&gt;self&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
