<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>Disable OpenGL for Python / Matplotlib</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;m doing a Python course for which I have installed Arch Linux in a VM. When I use Matplotlib.pyplot to plot things (x vs y) I get a bunch of errors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;libGL error: pci id for fd 12: 80ee:beef, driver (null)OpenGL Warning: glFlushVertexArrayRangeNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glVertexArrayRangeNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glCombinerInputNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glCombinerOutputNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glCombinerParameterfNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glCombinerParameterfvNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glCombinerParameteriNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glCombinerParameterivNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glFinalCombinerInputNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGetCombinerInputParameterfvNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGetCombinerInputParameterivNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGetCombinerOutputParameterfvNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGetCombinerOutputParameterivNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGetFinalCombinerInputParameterfvNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGetFinalCombinerInputParameterivNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glDeleteFencesNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glFinishFenceNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGenFencesNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glGetFenceivNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glIsFenceNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glSetFenceNV not found in mesa tableOpenGL Warning: glTestFenceNV not found in mesa tablelibGL error: core dri or dri2 extension not foundlibGL error: failed to load driver: vboxvideoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfoOpenGL Warning: XGetVisualInfo returned 0 visuals for 00007f6ff33d0240OpenGL Warning: Retry with 0x8002 returned 0 visualsOpenGL Warning: glXGetFBConfigAttrib for 00007f6ff33d0240, failed to get XVisualInfo&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I turn of 3D support for the VM it simply asks for openGL. My script does create a plot (empty canvas) but without a line.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think it should be possible to draw some lines without openGL, right? How to go about this...&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit: I think it was a VirtualBox bug combined with an error in my Python code. I could actually get good graphs with the error messages present in the end. In the latest versions of VirtualBox I&#x27;m not getting the error anymore. Thanx for the suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
<Tags>linux,opengl,python-3.x,matplotlib,virtualbox</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;so, despite of all the errors, I never had anything not working actually, the fact that I didn&#x27;t see graphs was not due to the error in the original post. It was something else, I guess unrelated tot mpl and more related to lack of 3D acceleration in VirtualBox.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
