<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<qroot>
<question>
<Title>Python: installing packages and downloads</Title>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;I am trying to set and install some packages with python. I have already installed python3 along with Anaconda.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My first question is that when I type:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ python3 &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anaconda says: &lt;code&gt;&quot;$&quot; is not an internal or external command&lt;/code&gt;. Should I be using a different command or how can I fix this?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;My second question is this: I am trying to install the packages from these four sites based on a book I got:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;NumPy: &lt;a href=&quot;http://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy-1.10.1/user/install.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://docs.scipy.org/doc/numpy-1.10.1/user/install.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;SciPy: &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.scipy.org/install.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://www.scipy.org/install.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;scikit-learn: &lt;a href=&quot;http://scikit-learn.org/stable/install.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://scikit-learn.org/stable/install.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;matplotlib: &lt;a href=&quot;http://matplotlib.org/1.4.2/users/installing.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;http://matplotlib.org/1.4.2/users/installing.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;This note was in there as well: &lt;em&gt;&quot;If you are on Windows, you should have installed a SciPy-stack compatible version of Python 3&quot;.&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I go to copy the line for installing the packages on windows and pasting it into my terminal, it gives the error: &lt;code&gt;&quot;The system can not find the file specified&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can I fix this?&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
<Tags>python</Tags>
</question>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&#x27;t type the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt;, just &lt;code&gt;python3&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The packages you mention are already included in Anaconda python distribution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;</Body>
</answer>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;p&gt;Just as emmv said, a few other things in my mind:You installed Python with Anaconda. I assume you did not add Python to PATH. You should check Anaconda website for any further installments, downloads etc. Anaconda uses a simple &quot;conda&quot; command, after all. Really, just look at Anaconda&#x27;s website if you are confused.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
<answer>
<Body>&lt;ol&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; is usually used to indicate the start of a line that should be executed in a terminal window. So, therefore, remove the &lt;code&gt;$&lt;/code&gt; and write everything that comes afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;If you installed Anaconda, then you should have the &lt;code&gt;conda&lt;/code&gt; command available to you. Besides &lt;code&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/code&gt;, the packages should already be installed with your Anaconda distribution. What you could do is &lt;code&gt;$ conda install scikit-learn&lt;/code&gt; and this should install &lt;code&gt;scikit-learn&lt;/code&gt; for you.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;I recommend you to look at the documentation of Anaconda at the Anaconda website (&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.anaconda.com/anaconda/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot;&gt;https://docs.anaconda.com/anaconda/&lt;/a&gt;) to learn more on how Anaconda, packages and Python works.&lt;/p&gt;</Body>
</answer>
</qroot>
